Guide to the Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements, 1871-2009 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements 1871-2009 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lightner, Roy, collector.
24.0 linear feet Extent: 20,000 Items
Roy Lightner was an advertising and marketing executive, primarily with N.W. Ayer & Son agency, from which he retired in 1980, and with Carden & Cherry Advertising of Nashville, Tenn. The Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements spans the years 1871-2009 and includes primarily print advertisements clipped from U.S. magazines. Also present are proofs of print advertisements and 16mm reels of television commercials, much of which was produced by the N.W. Ayer & Son agency during Lightner's career there. Advertisements predominantly focus on automobiles, railroads, insurance companies and manufacturers of brand name consumer goods. Over 300 companies are represented in the collection, including AT&T, Buick, Cadillac, Campbell's, Chevrolet, Chrysler, Coca-Cola, Dodge, Du Pont, Kodak, Ford, General Electric, General Mills, General Motors, Lincoln-Mercury, Metropolitan Life, Oldsmobile, Packard, Plymouth, Pontiac, RCA, and Studebaker.Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00814
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2002-2009.
Biographical Note
Roy Lightner Biographical Timeline
1921 Born, Wyomissing, Pa.
1942 Graduated, Franklin & Marshall College, Lancaster, Pa.
1942-1946 Production Planner, Production Supervisor, N.W. Ayer Philadelphia
1947-1952 Account Supervisor, N.W. Ayer Boston
1956 Account Executive, N.W. Ayer Philadelphia
1963 Account Supervisor, N.W. Ayer Philadelphia
1970 Vice President and Account Manager, N.W. Ayer Philadelphia
1980 Retired from N.W. Ayer; assumed Directorship of United Methodist Church television ministry campaign
1982 Vice President, Marketing Services, Carden & Cherry Advertising, Nashville, Tenn.
1982-1988 Oversaw production of "Ernest P. Worrell--Vern" commercials starring Jim Varney
The following clients, represented in this collection, were served by Lightner during his tenure at N.W. Ayer: AT&T, Boeing, Breyer's, Cannon towels, Capehart, Carrier, Caterpillar, Chrysler, Clicquot Club, Container Corporation of America, DeBeers, Dole, Du Pont, Electric Companies, Forstman, French Line, General Electric, Goodyear, Hanes, Hess & Clark, Hires Root Beer, I.C.S., Insurance Companies of North America, Kellogg's, Maine Development Commission, Masonite, National Bible Week, National Dairy Products, New England Mutual, Nicholson File Co., N.W. Ayer, Oxirane, Penn Mutual, Plymouth, Red Heart Dog Food, Regal Shoes, Sani-Flush, Sealtest, Sergent's, Sheffield Farms, Steinway, Texaco, Times Mirror Magazine Network, TV Guide, U.S. Army Recruiting, Warren Telechron, and Yardley.
Collection Overview
The Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements spans the years 1871-2009 and includes primarily print advertisements clipped from U.S. magazines. Also present are proofs of print advertisements and 16mm reels of television commercials, much of which was produced by the N.W. Ayer & Son agency during Lightner's career there. Advertisements predominantly focus on automobiles, railroads, insurance companies and manufacturers of brand name consumer goods. Over 300 companies are represented in the collection, including AT&T, Buick, Cadillac, Campbell's, Chevrolet, Chrysler, Coca-Cola, Dodge, Du Pont, Kodak, Ford, General Electric, General Mills, General Motors, Lincoln-Mercury, Metropolitan Life, Oldsmobile, Packard, Plymouth, Pontiac, RCA, and Studebaker.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged in 6 series: General Goods and Services; Cars and Trucks; Norman Rockwell Collection; N.W. Ayer Materials; Roy Lightner Files; and Oversize Materials. General Goods and Services include all print advertisements except car and truck advertisements, arranged alphabetically by product or company name. Cars and Trucks include print advertisements for automobiles, personal and commercial trucks and some corporate advertising from automotive companies, arranged alphabetically by vehicle make. The Norman Rockwell Collection consists of a set of advertisements, magazine covers and other illustrations featuring artwork by Norman Rockwell, arranged chronologically. The N.W. Ayer Materials consists primarily printed materials by or about the N.W. Ayer agency, along with some television commercials produced for Du Pont. Roy Lightner Files include handwritten inventories of advertisements included in this collection along with some clippings and memorabilia relating to Lightner's career. Oversize Materials include large-format materials removed from other series and housed separately, arranged to mirror the rest of the collection.
Subject Headings
Lightner, Roy, 1921-; N.W. Ayer & Son; American Telephone and Telegraph Company; Cadillac Motor Car Company; Campbell Soup Company; Chrysler Corporation; Chrysler Corporation. Dodge Division; Coca-Cola Company; Eastman Kodak Company; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company; Ford Motor Car Company; General Electric Company; General Mills, Inc.; General Motors Corporation; General Motors Corporation. Buick Motor Division; General Motors Corporation. Cadillac Motor Car Division; General Motors Corporation. Chevrolet Motor Division; Lincoln Motor Car Company (Detroit, Mich.); Metropolitan Life Insurance Company; Packard Motor Car Company; Radio Corporation of America; Studebaker-Packard Corporation; Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Automobiles; Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States; Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Brand name products; Advertising -- Brand name products -- United States; Advertising -- Brand name products -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Insurance; Advertising -- Insurance -- United States; Advertising -- Insurance -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Railroads; Advertising -- Railroads -- United States; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; 16mm; Proofs (Printed material); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives
Jeffrey Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials
Jim Brown Papers
Jim Varney Collection of Advertising
John Benjamin Harris Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements Collection
J. Walter Thompson Company. Edgar Hatcher Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Samuel W. Meek Papers
Walter Weir Papers
- General Products and Services--Small Format, 1871-2009, (7 boxes)
  - Alcoa, 1931-1937 (Box 1)
  - American Express, 1918-2000 (Box 1)
  - American Gas Association, 1947-1972, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - American Radiator Company (Standard Sanitary Mfg. Co.), 1900-1924 (Box 1)
  - American Sugar Refining (Domino brand), 1903-1915 (Box 1)
  - Anacin, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
  - Andrew Jergens (includes Woodbury), 1897-1970 (Box 1)
  - Anheuser-Busch, 1896-1911 (Box 1)
  - Armour, 1897-1962 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong Cork, 1967-1987 (Box 1)
  - Arrow Shirts (Cluett Peabody), 1898-1962, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - AT&T (American Telephone and Telegraph, Bell System), 1909-1989, (1-10 of 11 folders) (Box 1)
  - AT&T (American Telephone and Telegraph, Bell System), 1909-1989, (11 of 11 folders) (Box 2)
  - Ayer's Cherry Pectoral, 1896-1900 (Box 2)
  - Baker's Cocoa/Chocolate, 1896-1958 (Box 2)
  - Bangor & Aroostook Railroad, 1902 (Box 2)
  - Bayer Aspirin, 1920-1977, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Beecham's Pills, 1898-1899 (Box 2)
  - Beeman's Chewing Gum, 1917-1919 (Box 2)
  - Bell & Howell, 1922-1948 (Box 2)
  - Best & Co., 1896-1904 (Box 2)
  - B.F. Goodrich, 1908-1970 (Box 2)
  - Bissell, 1903-1921 (Box 2)
  - Bixby Shoe Polish, 1909 (Box 2)
  - Boeing, 1942-1966 (Box 2)
  - Bon Ami, 1903-1970 (Box 2)
  - Book of the Month Club, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Borden's, 1899-1979 (Box 2)
  - Boston & Maine Railroad, 1902-1910 (Box 2)
  - Boston Garter, 1903-1904 (Box 2)
  - Breck, 1959-1974 (Box 2)
  - Breyer's, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Brillo, 1924-1960, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Bromo-Seltzer, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Brooks Brothers, 1910-1911 (Box 2)
  - Brunswick Billiard Tables, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Bryant Heating, 1927-1931 (Box 2)
  - Burlington Route, 1898-1965 (Box 2)
  - Burnett's Vanilla, 1899-1913 (Box 2)
  - Burnham and Morrill, 1910-1951 (Box 2)
  - Burpee's Seeds, 1904-1918 (Box 2)
  - Butcher's Polish, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Butterick Publishing, 1896 (Box 2)
  - BVD, 1908-1919 (Box 2)
  - Calder's Dentine, 1898-1899 (Box 2)
  - Calox Tooth Powder, 1903-1918 (Box 2)
  - Camay, 1934-1966 (Box 2)
  - Camel, 1919-1934 (Box 2)
  - Campbell's Soup, 1906-1975, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Canadian National, 1921-1949 (Box 2)
  - Canadian Pacific, 1899-1958 (Box 2)
  - Cannon Towels, 1942-1974 (Box 2)
  - Carnation Milk, 1924-1967 (Box 2)
  - Carter's underwear, 1957-1972 (Box 2)
  - Castoria, 1898-1899 (Box 2)
  - Chef Boy-Ar-Dee, 1959-1973 (Box 2)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway, 1902 (Box 2)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1905-1942 (Box 2)
  - Chicago & NOrthwestern Railway, 1898-1906 (Box 2)
  - Chickering Pianos, 1871-1905 (Box 2)
  - Chris-Craft, 1929-1967 (Box 2)
  - Cleveland Baking Powder, 1896-1897 (Box 2)
  - Clicquot Club, 1908-1952 (Box 2)
  - Clorox, 1946-1960 (Box 2)
  - Coca-Cola (includes Fanta, Sprite), 1902-1949, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Coca-Cola (includes Fanta, Sprite), 1950-1999, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Coca-Cola Santa Advertisements, 1933-1960 (Box 3)
  - Colgate, 1901-1973, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Colt firearms, 1906-1929 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Phonograph, 1904-1920 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Soups, 1898 (Box 3)
  - Conard Roses, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Cook's Flaked Rice, 1902 (Box 3)
  - Corbin, 1918-1930 (Box 3)
  - Corliss Coon Collars, 1902-1903 (Box 3)
  - Corona Typewriter, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Cosmo Soap, 1898 (Box 3)
  - Crane, 1920-1931 (Box 3)
  - Cream of Wheat, 1899-1967 (Box 3)
  - Crest Toothpaste, 1957-1973 (Box 3)
  - Crisco, 1924-1991 (Box 3)
  - Cross Pen, 1969-1998 (Box 3)
  - Cudahy's Flavor, 1896 (Box 3)
  - Cuticura Soap, 1894-1923 (Box 3)
  - De Beers, 1956-1983 (Box 3)
  - Del Monte, 1923-1991 (Box 3)
  - Dent's Toothache Gum, 1902-1904 (Box 3)
  - Diamond Crystal Salt, 1924, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Dingee & Conard Roses, 1899-1928 (Box 3)
  - Dixon Pencils, 1893-1940 (Box 3)
  - Dole Pineapple, 1911-1975 (Box 3)
  - Dooley's Yeast, 1871 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Gouraud's Oriental Cream, 1897-1904 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Jaeger's Underwear, 1898-1899 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Scott's Electric Belt/Hair Brush, 1896-1905 (Box 3)
  - Dunham's Coconut, 1899 (Box 3)
  - Du Pont, 1906-1991, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Durkee's Seasonings, 1898 (Box 3)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1894-1920s, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1930s-1979, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Edison Phonograph, 1898-1919 (Box 4)
  - Electro-Silicon Silver Polish, 1896-1911 (Box 4)
  - Elgin Watch, 1898-1949 (Box 4)
  - Enameline, 1898-1901 (Box 4)
  - Equitable Society, 1902-1942 (Box 4)
  - Eskay Foods (Smith, Kline and French), 1902-1910 (Box 4)
  - Esterbrook Pens, 1902-1953 (Box 4)
  - Eveready, 1919-1941 (Box 4)
  - Eversharp, 1921-1928 (Box 4)
  - Fairbanks (includes Fairy Soap), 1896-1916 (Box 4)
  - Fels Naptha, 1921 (Box 4)
  - Ferris Corsets, 1899-1923 (Box 4)
  - Ferry's Seeds, 1899-1906 (Box 4)
  - Firestone, 1916-1922 (Box 4)
  - Florsheim Shoes, 1904-1922 (Box 4)
  - Forhan's Toothpaste, 1920-1923 (Box 4)
  - Franco-American, 1908-1973 (Box 4)
  - French Line, 1918-1938 (Box 4)
  - Frigidaire, 1924-1991 (Box 4)
  - Frisco System, 1902 (Box 4)
  - Gem Razors, 1902-1909 (Box 4)
  - General Electric, 1909-1991, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - General Mills [Includes Betty Crocker, Gold Medal, Washburn-Crosby], 1903-1992 (Box 4)
  - General Motors Electromotive Division, 1943-1949 (Box 4)
  - General Tire, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Gerber's, 1934-1970 (Box 4)
  - Gillette, 1904-1932 (Box 4)
  - Goblin Soap (Cudahy), 1918 (Box 5)
  - Gold Dust, 1894-1931 (Box 5)
  - Goodyear, 1913-1973, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Great Northern Railway, 1919-1948 (Box 5)
  - Green Giant, 1952, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Greyhound, 1937-1947 (Box 5)
  - Hamilton Watch, 1920-1939 (Box 5)
  - Hammond Organ, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - Hanes, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hart Schaffner and Marx, 1899-1924 (Box 5)
  - Hartshorn Shade Roller, 1896-1911 (Box 5)
  - Hawaii Tourism, 1921-1960 (Box 5)
  - Hellmann's (Best Foods), 1953-1974 (Box 5)
  - Hercules Powder, 1918 (Box 5)
  - Hess & Clark, 1923 (Box 5)
  - Hires Root Beer, 1894-1974 (Box 5)
  - H.J. Heinz, 1901-1960 (Box 5)
  - Hodgson Houses, 1921-1937 (Box 5)
  - Hoover, 1919-1969 (Box 5)
  - Hormel, 1911-1967 (Box 5)
  - Hunt's, 1959-1972 (Box 5)
  - Huyler's Chocolate, 1896-1917 (Box 5)
  - Ingersoll Watch, 1902-1923 (Box 5)
  - International Correspondence Schools, 1901-1960 (Box 5)
  - International Silver, 1896-1924 (Box 5)
  - Iver Johnson firearms, 1896-1911 (Box 5)
  - Ivory, 1894-1974 (Box 5)
  - J.B. Williams, 1898-1952 (Box 5)
  - Jello, 1903-1975 (Box 5)
  - John Holland Pens, 1901-1905 (Box 5)
  - Johnson and Johnson, 1921-1975, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Joseph Gillott's Pens, 1871-1898 (Box 5)
  - Karo, 1909-1972 (Box 5)
  - Keen Kutter Scissors, 1906 (Box 5)
  - Kellogg's, 1907-1973 (Box 5)
  - Kelly Springfield, 1899-1926, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Kitchenaid, 1928-1989 (Box 5)
  - Klaxon, 1910 (Box 5)
  - Knox, 1898-1974 (Box 5)
  - Kraft, 1923-1977 (Box 5)
  - Kuppenheimer, 1904-1909 (Box 5)
  - La Blanche Face Powder, 1896-1914 (Box 5)
  - Lake Shore & Michigan Southern Railroad, 1898-1902 (Box 5)
  - Lackawanna Railroad, 1899-1902 (Box 5)
  - Laughlin Fountain Pens, 1900-1905 (Box 5)
  - Lea & Perrins, 1908-1910 (Box 5)
  - Lehigh Valley Railroad, 1898-1902 (Box 5)
  - Leitz, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Libby, 1878-1962 (Box 5)
  - Liebig Extract of Beef, 1871-1921 (Box 5)
  - Lifebuoy, 1902-1935 (Box 5)
  - Lifesavers, 1928-1991 (Box 6)
  - Listerine, 1914-1989 (Box 6)
  - Lord & Taylor, 1871-1908 (Box 6)
  - Louisville & Nashville Railroad, 1929-1931 (Box 6)
  - Lux, 1924-1952, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Lysol, 1924 (Box 6)
  - Maine Tourism, 1928-1948 (Box 6)
  - Malvina Cream, 1898-1901 (Box 6)
  - Masonite, 1931 (Box 6)
  - Maxwell House, 1922-1924, 1970-1991 (Box 6)
  - Mazola, 1958-1973 (Box 6)
  - Mellin's Food, 1892-1910 (Box 6)
  - Mennen, 1896-1911, 1951-1960 (Box 6)
  - Metropolitan Life, 1923-1960, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Metropolitan Life Peanuts campaign, 1984-1998 (Box 6)
  - Michelin, 1908-1922 (Box 6)
  - Milwaukee Road, 1906-1948 (Box 6)
  - Minute Rice, 1959-1991 (Box 6)
  - Missouri, Kansas & Texas Railroad, 1871 (Box 6)
  - Mobil Oil, 1918, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Modene Hair Removal, 1896-1904 (Box 6)
  - Moller's Cod Liver Oil, 1871-1872, 1906 (Box 6)
  - Monon Route, 1898-1904 (Box 6)
  - Mutual Life Insurance, 1907 (Box 6)
  - Nabisco (includes Uneeda), 1899-1958, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - National Bible Week, 1979 (Box 6)
  - National Cash Register, 1908-1909 (Box 6)
  - National Dairy Products, 1943-1947 (Box 6)
  - National Fluid Milk Producers (Got Milk campaign), 1995-2009 (Box 6)
  - Nestlé, 1900-1909, 1958-19894 (Box 6)
  - New England Mutual, 1935-1937 (Box 6)
  - New York Central, 1898-1949 (Box 6)
  - Nicholson File Co., 1942-1962 (Box 6)
  - Northern Pacific, 1898-1929, 1950s (Box 6)
  - N.W. Ayer house advertisements, 1898-1902 (Box 6)
  - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1910-1959 (Box 6)
  - Ostermoor Mattress, 1899-1911 (Box 6)
  - Pabst, 1896-1942 (Box 6)
  - Packer's Tar Soap, 1897-1923 (Box 6)
  - Palmolive, 1922-1991 (Box 6)
  - Pan American World Airways (Pan Am), 1979 (Box 6)
  - Pantasote Leather, 1910 (Box 6)
  - Parker Pen, 1898-1992 (Box 6)
  - Paul E. Wirt Pens, 1901-1905 (Box 7)
  - Pearline, 1896-1911 (Box 7)
  - Pear's Soap, 1896-1914 (Box 7)
  - Penn Mutual, 1899-1949 (Box 7)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Pepsodent, 1918-1932, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Pet Milk, 1924, 1958-1964 (Box 7)
  - Peter's Chocolate, 1910 (Box 7)
  - Phoenix Mutual, 1898-1902 (Box 7)
  - Pillsbury, 1892-1992, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Ping-Pong (Parker Brothers game), 1902 (Box 7)
  - Planter's Peanuts, 1927 (Box 7)
  - Pneumatic Bell, 1871 (Box 7)
  - Polaroid, 1949-1986 (Box 7)
  - Post/Postum (General Foods), 1899-1925, 1951, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Pratt & Lambert, 1901-1924 (Box 7)
  - Prestone, 1937-1939 (Box 7)
  - Prince Albert, 1910-1928 (Box 7)
  - Pro-Phy-Lac-Tic, 1894-1928 (Box 7)
  - Prudential, 1897-1996, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Pullman, 1937-1949 (Box 7)
  - Pyorrhocide, 1920-1923 (Box 7)
  - Pyrex, 1916-1946, 1962, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Quaker Oats, 1897-1974 (Box 7)
  - Quaker/Pettijohn, 1899-1915 (Box 7)
  - Quaker Puffed Rice/Wheat, 1906-1965, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Ralston-Purina, 1900-1910, 1973, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Rat Bis-Kit, 1902-1920 (Box 7)
  - RCA Victor (includes Victor Talking Machines, Victrola, Radiola, Victor and Red Seal Records, Whirlpool), 1902-1966, (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - Red Heart Dog Food, 1937-1951 (Box 7)
  - Reed & Barton, 1871, 1897 (Box 7)
  - Regal Shoes, 1898-1914 (Box 7)
  - Remington Typewriter, 1899-1926 (Box 7)
  - Resinol Soap, 1904-1923 (Box 7)
  - Rice Council, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Richardson & Robbins, 1923-1924, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Rinso, 1932-1933 (Box 7)
  - Rio Grande Railroad, 1954-1956 (Box 8)
  - Rock Island Line, 1899-1932 (Box 8)
  - Roper Ranges, 1923-1924 (Box 8)
  - Royal (Baking Powder, Gelatin desserts), 1896-1955 (Box 8)
  - Royal-Worcester/Bon Ton corsets, 1903-1906 (Box 8)
  - R.T. French, 1931-1973 (Box 8)
  - Rubens Infant Shirt, 1902-1922 (Box 8)
  - Rubiform Dentifrice, 1896-1906 (Box 8)
  - Russwin Hardware, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Sani-Flush, 1918-1951 (Box 8)
  - Santa Fe Railroad, 1897-1949 (Box 8)
  - Sapolin, 1909 (Box 8)
  - Sapolio, 1896-1913 (Box 8)
  - Sargent Locks and Hardware, 1924 (Box 8)
  - S.C. Johnson & Sons, 1904-1960, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Scott Paper, 1911-1973 (Box 8)
  - Seaboard Railway, 1902-1905 (Box 8)
  - Sears, Roebuck & Co., 1898-1909 (Box 8)
  - Sergent's Pet Supplies, 1934-1952 (Box 8)
  - Sheaffer Pens, 1918-1979, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Sheaffer Pens, 1918-1979 (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Sheffield Farms, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Shredded Wheat, 1900-1952 (Box 8)
  - Simmons Mattresses, 1918-1931, 1968-1973 (Box 8)
  - Singer Sewing Machine Co., 1898-1908, 1951-1979 (Box 8)
  - Smith Typewriters, 1898-1908 (Box 8)
  - SOS Scouring Pads, 1924-1955 (Box 8)
  - Southern Pacific Railroad, 1902-1948 (Box 8)
  - Southern Railway, 1898, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Spencerian Pens, 1900-1924 (Box 8)
  - Squibb, 1921-1945 (Box 8)
  - Steinway Pianos, 1898-1939 (Box 8)
  - Sunmaid, 1921-1924, 1942, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Sunsweet, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Swans Down, 1923-1924, 1951-1960 (Box 8)
  - Swift and Co., 1900-1991 (Box 8)
  - Taylor Instruments, 1920-1937 (Box 8)
  - Testimonial advertising, 1902-1979 (Box 8)
  - Texaco (includes Havoline), 1910-1948, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Thos. Cook, 1898-1930 (Box 8)
  - Tiffany Jewelers, 1871-1931 (Box 8)
  - Traveler's Insurance (See also Metropolitan Life folders for additional advertisements), 1901-1960 (Box 8)
  - Underwood Foods, 1899-1974 (Box 8)
  - Union Pacific, 1896-1966 (Box 8)
  - United Airlines, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
  - United States Army Recruiting, 1964-1986 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Rubber (U.S. Tires), 1916-1923 (Box 8)
  - Vapo-Cresolene, 1896-1921 (Box 8)
  - Vose Pianos, 1896-1922 (Box 8)
  - Wabash Railroad, 1898-1904 (Box 8)
  - Wanamaker, 1902-1918 (Box 9)
  - Warren Telechron, 1929-1931 (Box 9)
  - Waterman Pens, 1898-1929, 1989 (Box 9)
  - WB Corsets, 1896-1903 (Box 9)
  - Wear-Ever, 1920-1921 (Box 9)
  - Weber Pianos, 1871-1908 (Box 9)
  - Welch's, 1902-1932 (Box 9)
  - Wesson, 1924-1977 (Box 9)
  - Westinghouse, 1940-1943 (Box 9)
  - Wheatena, 1898-1899 (Box 9)
  - Whitman's Chocolates, 1894-1933, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Wilbur Bros. Chocolate, 1908-1924 (Box 9)
  - Winchester firearms, 1904-1908 (Box 9)
  - Winslow's Syrup, 1897-1898 (Box 9)
  - W.L. Douglas shoes, 1904-1937 (Box 9)
  - Woman's Institute, 1924-1930 (Box 9)
  - Wool Soap, 1899-1903 (Box 9)
  - Wrigley's, 1914-1972 (Box 9)
  - Yardley, 1926 (Box 9)
  - Zenith, 1949-1959 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Apparel, 1896-1944 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Bicycles, etc., 1894-1899 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Books/Publications, 1896-1949 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Businesses, 1871-1934 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Education/Schools, etc., 1896-1926 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Employment offers, 1871-1929 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Food & Beverage, 1896-1928 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Health & Beauty, 1896-1944 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous House & Garden, 1896-1942 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Musical Instruments, 1896-1902 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Novelties & Notions, 1896-1927 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Patent Medicines/Cures ("Quacks"), 1871-1926 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Pens, Pencils, 1897-1948 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Sporting Goods/Firearms, 1902-1928 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Tobacco, 1899-1914 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Travel & Transportation, 1898-1949 (Box 9)
- General Products and Services--Large Format, 1894-2009, (8 boxes)
  - Adams Chewing Gum, 1918 (Box 10)
  - Aetna Casualty, 1931, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Alcoa, 1949 (Box 10)
  - American Brakeblok, 1937 (Box 10)
  - American Express, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - American Gas Association, 1936-1974 (Box 10)
  - American Radiator Company (Standard Sanitary Mfg. Co.), 1917-1958 (Box 10)
  - Anacin, 1955-1961 (Box 10)
  - Andrew Jergens (includes Woodbury), 1920-1956 (Box 10)
  - Anheuser-Busch, 1938 (Box 10)
  - Armour, 1906-1955 (Box 10)
  - Armstrong Cork, 1920-1987 (Box 10)
  - Arrow Shirts (Cluett Peabody), 1942-1955 (Box 10)
  - Arvin Car Heater, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Association of American Railroads, 1937 (Box 10)
  - AT&T (American Telephone and Telegraph, Bell System), 1922-1989, (4 folders) (Box 10)
  - Aunt Jemima, 1917-1968 (Box 10)
  - Aviso, 1956-1960 (Box 10)
  - Avon, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Baker's Cocoa Chocolate, 1912-1956 (Box 10)
  - Baker's Coconut, 1923-1970 (Box 10)
  - Baltimore & Ohio, 1924-1957 (Box 10)
  - Barbasol, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Bayer Aspirin, 1930-1973 (Box 10)
  - Beech-Nut Gum, 1917-1919 (Box 10)
  - B.F. Goodrich, 1930 (Box 10)
  - Bissell, 1930 (Box 10)
  - Bixby Shoe Polish, 1909 (Box 10)
  - Blue Bell, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Boeing, 1944-1969 (Box 10)
  - Bon Ami, 1918-1939 (Box 10)
  - Borden's, 1929-1958 (Box 10)
  - Bostich, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Breck, 1958-1973 (Box 10)
  - Brillo, 1924-1939 (Box 10)
  - Bromo-Seltzer, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Brooks Brothers, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Bruning, 1965-1970 (Box 10)
  - Budd, 1946-1949 (Box 10)
  - Bufferin, 1955-1973 (Box 10)
  - Burlington Route, 1924-1967 (Box 10)
  - Burnham and Morrill, 1942-1958 (Box 10)
  - Buster Brown, 1924, 1959 (Box 10)
  - BVD, 1919 (Box 10)
  - Camay, 1930-1939 (Box 11)
  - Camel, 1919-1935 (Box 11)